♪Myriad delusions cut like knives♪
♪Crushing the moon in the ancient well♪
♪Lost in this life,
I never ask about tomorrow♪
♪When love runs deep,
the moonlight fades♪
♪A cursed fate,
a dream severed over lifetimes♪
=Braving the Famine with My Wife=
=Episode 5=
While that fool Zhao Dong is gone,
let's all run away now.
No matter where we run,
it'll end the same.
I'm not running.
This is my fate.
The world is in chaos right now.
Where could we even go?
(No.)
(Dong can only be mine.)
(I have to get rid of them.)
Actually, there's something
I've been struggling to tell you.
Last night,
the shameless Zhao Dong
forced himself on me.
And...
He's covered in sores,
reeking to high heaven.
Why do I feel itchy all over?
I think he infected me!
What am I going to do?
(Why do I feel like she's acting?)
My ladies, I'm back.
Dong!
Miss Su, be careful.
Stay away from him.
Ladies,
let me bear this suffering alone.
As long as you're safe,
I'll be at ease.
Dong!
Dong, you're back. Let's go.
(Su Wan'er lied. What's her game?)
(Affection -100)
(What's going on?)
(Their affections all hit rock bottom.)
(How to dual cultivate?)
I came into some money last night.
I bought you some fine wine, food,
and new clothes.
What are you waiting for?
Sit down and eat.
After you eat, try on the new clothes.
Dong,
they're not really hungry.
Don't force them.
Zhao Dong, you are unbelievably foolish.
This windfall could have bought
over 30 jin of grain.
Instead, you wasted it.
New month in a few days.
Fail to deliver the grain,
and we're all going to suffer.
Exactly.
Since you're the head of this family,
you should think about everyone.
When the officials come,
what will you give them?
If we end up in jail for this,
we'll be done for good.
A moment of pleasure,
ruin beyond redemption.
You... You've truly disappointed me.
The revenue officer at the county office
is gravely ill.
No physician in the region can help him.
I plan to step in and save his life
in exchange for supplies.
You don't know your place.
How dare you provoke the authorities?
Are you trying
to make things worse for us?
Yeah. Everyone around here
knows exactly who you are.
We can't do
such underhanded, crooked schemes.
(You silly girls have no idea
what Dong's capable of.)
(The more you do this,)
(the more he'll despise you.)
If I cure the revenue officer,
you'll all spend the night with me.
What do you say? Do we have a bet?
No, I'm not betting on that.
If you win,
I promise I won't touch you.
I'll take that bet.
If you fail to heal him,
you absolutely cannot touch me.
Fine. Sign it and seal it.
No backing out.
(Zhang Mansion)
Dong, this outfit you bought me
fits perfectly.
Dong, they're holding a funeral here.
Is the officer already dead?
(Great, he's definitely going to lose.)
We agreed
that if he is dead, you lose.
And you can't touch me.
It's in black and white,
sealed and signed.
Hanyan, you're twisting the terms.
But, I'll allow it.
Dong, so you can't touch her then.
Dong, what do you know about medicine?
He is already dead.
Just find a graceful way out.
I said he won't die.
Even Death wouldn't take him.
Let's go.
(Oh, no. He's completely insane.)
(If he causes trouble,
the whole family will pay.)
(Oh, my! Why did I have to end up
with a man like this?)
(Affection -101)
Zhao Laizi,
come here begging?
You're dressed all fancy today.
Where did you steal those clothes?
Watch your filthy mouth.
Dong, he insulted you. I...
Not only did your two wives
not starve to death,
they're looking even more radiant.
You got a real bargain.
(How dare you mock Dong?)
(You're asking for it.)
This family is really something.
How can they allow stray dogs to bark
in the mourning hall?
You lowly fool!
What makes you think you belong here?
Get out, now!
Let's just go.
Don't cause trouble.
Are you trying to get us all killed?
I'm here to treat Master Zhang.
Don't worry.
A country bumpkin like you
dares to spout nonsense here?
Master Zhang has passed away.
Are you here to summon his spirit?
You're just asking for death!
I'll just ignore you ignorant fools.
Wan'er,
Hanyan,
follow me inside to save a life.
You're putting on an act with me?
Someone! Break this fool's legs!
And drag these two lowborn women
to the back room.
I'll interrogate them slowly later.
Get them!
How did you end up on the ground?
Looks like all those wild nights
have ruined your body.
You're asking for it!
Stop!
My Lord, Zhao Dong has come
to stir up trouble.
He even falsely claims
he can revive Master Zhang.
But Master Zhang
has already passed away.
He's clearly insulting the Zhang family!
He deserves death.
Darn it!
Master Zhang's time hasn't come yet.
Today is the day he rises from the dead.
If I fail to revive him,
I'll accept any punishment.
(This fool is really
going all the way with this.)
(Heaven is dooming my Liu family.)
(Can Dong really bring the dead
back to life?)
(Stuck in a terrible position now,)
(I just hope Dong doesn't let me down.)
My Lord,
since Zhao Dong is so confident,
why not let him give it a try?
On the off chance
a miracle actually happens.
Today is the day of Yisi.
Si Fire clashes with Hai Water.
Master Zhang's fate is of water.
Excessive fire rushed to the heart,
sealing off his breath.
There's still a thread of life,
three cun
beneath Zigong and Yutang acupoints,
sealed there.
Fine.
Since you speak with such conviction,
I'll let you try.
But if you fail to revive my father,
I will make sure the four of you
beg for death
and be denied it.
Wan'er, we're finished.
I told you we couldn't trust him.
Don't be afraid.
We have to believe in Dong.
It's okay. Let's go.
Go.
Zhao Laizi,
you're digging your own grave,
and dragging two pretty ladies
into this.
Call the boys back.
Yes, sir.
♪With a clap of thunder,
you were cast into the mortal realm♪
♪Silk robes replaced by rags♪
♪Immortal bones buried in the dust♪
♪One thought once stirred the seas♪
♪Now, even cold porridge
is a lucky find♪
♪She was cast out of the golden hall♪
♪With only half a tattered decree♪
♪Her eyes still held a blade's edge♪
♪Saying this world
isn't worth a single moment♪
♪You handed her a bowl of coarse tea♪
♪Telling her to taste
life's bitter and sweet♪
♪So the Supreme Immortal
can fall to dust♪
♪So the Empress
can feel her heart turn cold♪
♪You watched the sunset
in a narrow alley with her♪
♪Hearing a child cry out in pain,
yet still laughing, so silly♪
♪So power is no match
for a bowl of warm porridge♪
♪So heaven can't compare
to a lamp in a broken hut♪
♪From strangers to aching hearts♪
♪From cold words to genuine care♪
♪In the humblest corners
of the mortal world♪
♪You met the most precious person♪
♪She said commoners are just numbers♪
♪You took her to see
the fields turned to scars♪
♪And the old man bent by firewood♪
♪A lifetime of bitterness
on his shoulders♪
♪For the first time,
she set aside her crown♪
♪And held an umbrella
for a drenched street vendor♪
♪You can no longer ride the clouds♪
♪But only toss and turn in the night♪
♪Still kneeling at Heaven's Gate
in your dreams♪
♪Only to wake up
with a flatbread she tossed at you♪
♪Saying, forget the gods♪
♪Just catch your breath first♪
♪So the Supreme Immortal
can fall to dust♪
♪So the Empress can turn for someone♪
♪No longer asking
who stands higher or mightier♪
♪Only asking who stands
at your heart's door now♪
♪If Heaven wants you to pass
through the street's rising smoke first♪
♪If the mortal world cannot hold you♪
♪Then carve the memories
into your palm lines♪
♪From laughter to devotion♪
♪From falling to innocence♪
♪If there's a next life, you'll still♪
♪Love a mortal once more
amidst this suffering♪